# Yajaira Mercedes

2057 SE Glen Ridge Drive Port Saint Lucie, FL 34952

Phone: (401) 440-9858 Email: tequiero1@msn.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dynamic and confident professional with diversified experience in logistics, office administration, management and customer service. Highly motivated, client focused, strong leadership, ability to build productive relationships. Strong attention to detail, resourceful in completing projects, response to continually changing environment, and able to multi-task. Translator for Spanish and Portuguese.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Document Management
Accounts Payable/ Receivables
Policies Procedures/ Recruit/ Mediation
Employee Relations/ Training
Bookkeeping/Cash Control/Cash Register

Billing/ Collections
Recording/ Posting Revenues/ Deposits
Maintaining Records
Public Speaking
Scheduling

Employee Evaluation Clerical/ Office Procedures Ordering/Stocking Product Display Inventory

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES: Microsoft Word, Excel, Spreadsheet, Introduction to QuickBooks

#### **EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

### Office Administration/ Management

- Provided office support for a large delivery service company by increasing employee retention and business sales by 50%
- Transcribed employee meetings, business procedures and auditing in Spanish and Portuguese to facilitate employee communication
- Trained and developed several employees in various industries establishing a cohesive team with positive outcomes to maximize company goals

### **Customer Service Support**

- Expanded business by introducing new products with results to increasing customer retention and satisfaction
- Maintained high level of professionalism with co-workers and customers ensuring company integrity reaching a 5 star reviews
- Improved dynamics of communication by implementing different source channels such as email, hand held devices, and other social networking sites to ensure prompt problem solving solutions

## Logistics

- Orchestrated and carefully transported goods and sensitive documents to its destination in a timely manner of importance with different tracking devices.
- Improved costs control by creating and rearranging routes for customers and employees by covering specific range of geographic area
- Monitored all transportation operation including quality control to ensure services met contract obligations, overseeing routing, dispatching, tracking and shipping activities

## Yajaira Mercedes Page 2

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Couriers and Messengers Manager 03/2015 - 07/2018

Lab Logistics, West Haven, CT

**Restaurant Manager** 02/2015 - 09/2017

Made in Mexico Restaurant, North Providence, RI

**Logistics Manager** 01/2015 -12/2016

Beavex, Taunton, MA

Store Operations/ Owner 08/2009-08/2014

M & J Convenience Store, Providence, RI

**Education and Training** 

Johnson & Wales University, Providence, RI Associate's Degree Business Administration